London calling, with Frenchmen speaking to their countrymen.
伦敦广播:法国人致其同胞的公告
Take a look at that. What a handsome sight...
看啊,多么动人的场面……
...the pride of the Third Reich.
……第三帝国的骄傲
The brave sergeant taking coffee to the beachgunners.
勇敢的中士送咖啡给滩头炮兵
So that's a sample of the master race in a pig's eye.
这就是猪猡眼中高等民族的一个例证
What's going on here?
怎么回事？
In this darkest hour, in the gloom of night...
在这黑暗的时刻,在这黑暗的夜里……
...we must not despair.
……我们没必要绝望
Let us keep our faith intact,unswerving!
我们要保持我们最初的信念,坚定不移!
For each of us...
为了我们每个人……
...deliverance is coming.
……自由正在来临
We need mines and obstacles along the whole coast.
我们要在整个海岸布下地雷和障碍物
At every beach, on every dune...
包括每一个海滩,每一个沙丘……
...on every rock.
……每一块礁石
How many have been installed?
已经布置了多少？
Four million, Herr Field Marshal.
四百万,陆军元帅
It has to be six million by May.
五月必须达到六百万 -
-Six million. -Our men are constantly deployed.
－六百万 －我们的人一刻未停
There's no point in even discussing rest.
根本没有提及休整的事 (德军第十五集团军司令 　汉斯・冯・萨尔穆特上将)
-The troops are completely exhausted. -My dear Herr von Salmuth...
－部队已经精疲力竭了 －亲爱的冯・萨尔穆特……
...which would your troops rather be...
……你更愿意让你的部下……
...exhausted or dead?
……筋疲力尽还是丧命？
Just look at it, gentlemen.
看看这,各位
How calm, how peaceful it is.
如此宁静详和
A strip of water between England and the Continent...
横亘在英国和欧陆之间的这片水域……
...between the Allies and us.
……盟军和我们各据一方
But beyond that peaceful horizon, a monster waits.
但是在那头平静的地平线上,潜伏着一头怪兽
A coiled spring of men, ships and planes...
整装待发的部队,军舰,和飞机……
...straining to be released against us.
……想要一举击溃我们
But not a single Allied soldier shall reach the shore.
但没有一名盟军士兵能登上这片海滩
Not a single Anglo-American shall set foot on the beaches.
没有一名盎格美利坚人能涉足这片海滩
Whenever or wherever this invasion may come, gentlemen...
无论这次入侵来自何时何地……
...I shall destroy the enemy there, at the water's edge.
……我都会将敌军歼灭在海岸边
Believe me, gentlemen.
相信我,各位
The first 24 hours of the invasion will be decisive.
入侵的头二十四小时将成为关键
For the Allies as well as the Germans, it will be the longest day...
对于盟军和我军来说,都将是最漫长的一天……
...the longest day.
……最漫长的一天
-The poem by Verlaine? -Yes, the first verse.
－魏尔伦(Paul Verlaine)的诗？ －是的,第一节(《秋歌》)
Play it back!
倒回重放!
Silence!
安静!
Frenchmen speaking to their countrymen.
法国人致其同胞的公告
Here are some personal messages.
这是一些与个人有关的口信
"The long sobs of the violins of autumn. "
“秋天的小提琴那长长的呜咽”
I repeat:
重复
Have you notified all commands?
有没有通知所有指挥部？
If Berlin is right, when we intercept the second verse...
如果柏林方面是对的,那我们截听到第二节时……
...it will mean the invasion will come within 24 hours.
……就表示入侵将在二十四小时内发动
Give me the text of the second verse.
给我看看第二节
"Wounds my heart with a monotonous languor."
“用单调的忧郁刺伤我的心”
We've intercepted hundreds of messages in the last year, hundreds!
去年我们截听了数以百计的信息,数以百计!
I've ordered alerts again and again.
我一而再再而三地下令戒备
Why should this poem mean more than other messages?
为什么这首诗会比其他信息有更多意味？
Tell me this:
告诉我
Does it give us any clue as to where they will land and when?
它会提供任何敌军何时何地入侵的线索吗？
Of course it doesn't.
当然不会
I have half a million men under my command.
有五十万军队由我指挥
How can I maintain discipline if I keep my troops on the alert...
如果我不断下令戒备的话,该如何维持军纪……
...just because a pair of nitwits in Berlin intercept a poem?
……就因为柏林一对傻瓜截听到的一首诗？
No, Blumentritt, no alert.
不,布鲁门特里特,不用戒备
And especially not in this weather.
尤其是在这种天气
-Anything else? -No, sir.
－还有事吗？ －没有,长官
Good morning, field marshal.
早,陆军元帅
-Any news? -Nothing important.
－有情况吗？ －没有什么要紧的情况
Fighter bombers hit the Pas-de-Calais yesterday afternoon.
昨天下午加莱遭到了轰炸
Nothing much happened last night. The storm.
昨晚没发生其他事,风暴要来了
That's all I'm interested in this morning, the storm.
我关心的只是今早这场风暴
It came from nowhere, blew my roses to bits.
不知从哪来的,把我的玫瑰都吹坏了
There are 5-foot waves in the Channel...
海峡上的浪有五英尺高……
...and winds of 30 to 40 miles per hour.
……风速每小时三十到四十英里
For the month of June...
以六月而言……
...it's the worst Channel storm in 20 years.
……是二十年来最恶劣的海峡风暴
My appointment at Berchtesgaden?
我到贝希特斯加登晋见元首的事怎么样了？ (隆美尔打算请求希特勒调遣两个装甲师到诺曼底)
General Jodl will see the Fuhrer today...
约德尔将军今天要去见元首……
...and confirm the appointment for you.
……并为您安排晋见
Will you still go to Germany as planned?
您还是要按计划去回德国吗？
Can you think of a better time?
还能找到更好的时间吗？
The weather is expected to continue like this for another week.
这种天气看来要持续到下星期
Snap it up. Jerk the lead.
快跟上,下一个
You expect us to eat this slop again?
又要我们吃这玩意？
I don't care what you do with it, mac.
我才不管你吃不吃,老兄
Eat it, throw it out.
不想吃,扔掉好了
I get paid for cooking it.
我靠做这个拿薪水
Come on. Put it on.
得了,添上吧
Snap it up.
快跟上
Jerk the lead.
下一个
Didn't you get any sleep?
你没睡觉吗？
Are you kidding? I haven't slept since we got here.
开玩笑,自打来这我就没睡过
I got the absolute lowdown.
我得到确切消息
It's on for tonight. For sure.
就在今晚,是真的
Yeah.
是吗？
I got in this crap game with this guy from F Company.
我和Ｆ连一个家伙掷骰子时听说的
-He's an orderly for some general. -Move it. Move it.
－他是个将军的传令兵 －快来,快来
Hey, Hutchy!
嘿,哈奇
Hutchy, I want to ask you something.
哈奇,我有事要问你
Hey, Hutchinson...
嘿,哈奇森……
...do you think they'd let me writehome? If it was really important?
……如果是重要行动,会让我们写信回家吗？
Not likely, mate. Security.
不可能,伙计,得保密
I don't think old Churchill trusts us.
老丘吉尔并不相信我们
It's the wife, you see. She's going to have a baby.
是写给我太太,她快生了
Your first, is it?
第一个孩子，是吧？
Oh, it's not mine, but I'm dead worried about her.
不是我的,但我很担心她
She's not too strong, you see.
她身体不是很好
Man, that stink.
老兄,那儿真臭
Diesel oil, backed-up toilets, vomit.
有柴油,临时厕所,呕吐物
And there ain't no place left to get sick in.
没有地方安置病号
The puke bags is full.
呕吐袋都满了
The fire buckets is full.
消防桶也吐满了
All we got left is our helmets.
只剩下钢盔还能用
June.
六月
Every June my old man used to take me camping...
我老头子每年六月总是带我去露营……
...up in the Blue Mountains.
……在蓝岭上边
We'd hunt and fish all day long.
我们整天都打猎钓鱼
And at night...
到了晚上……
...we'd sleep out under the stars.
……我们就睡在星光之下
Didn't even need a blanket.
连毛毯都不用
June.
六月
Wind and rain. Wind and rain.
又是风,又是雨
Don't it ever stop?
还有完没完？
Look, Dad, all I want to do is get going.
看,老爹,我只想着出发
Wind or no wind. Even if we land in Paris on the Eiffel Tower.
管它风还是雨,哪怕降落在艾菲尔铁塔上都行
-Come to think of it-- -Colonel wants us.
－想想看…… －中校找我们
All of us.
所有人
I've notified the adjutant, change in schedule.
我接到通知,计划有变
After briefing session today...
今天碰头会之后……
...all troops will participate in ground tactics and deployment.
……所有部队都要参与地面作战布署
In this weather, sir?
在这种天气吗,头？
Of course, Harding, if you can ensure that we'll land in France...
当然,哈丁,你能保证降落在法国时……
-...in sunshine and dry weather. -Didn't mean that.
－……是大晴天吗？ －我不是这意思
-What did you mean? -It isn't the weather.
－那是什么意思？ －不是指天气
It's the waiting. These men are itching to go.
是等待时间,大伙都等不及了
I don't think I have to remind you...
我想用不着我来提醒你……
...that this war has been going on for almost five years.
……这场战争已经持续将近五年了
Half of Europe has been overrun and occupied.
半个欧洲遭到侵占
We're comparative newcomers.
我们是属于新来的
England's gone through a blitz with a knife at her throat since 1940.
英国从一九四○年起就一直面临入侵，如芒在背
I am quite sure that they too are impatient and itching to go.
我相信他们也迫不及待地想要反攻
Do I make myself clear?
说得够清楚了吗？
Yes, sir. Quite clear.
是的,头,很清楚
Three million men penned up on this island.
有三百万人驻扎在这个岛上
All over England, in staging areas like this.
象这样的兵营遍及整个英格兰
We're on the threshold of the most crucial day of our times.
我们正处在有史以来最重要时刻的前沿
Three million men out there...
三百万人在这……
...keyed up, and waiting for that big step-off.
……蓄势待发,就为了这一刻
They aren't exactly alone.
实际上不止是他们
Notify the men. Full packs and equipment, 1400 hours.
通知部队,下午二点前收拾好行装
Yes, sir.
是,头
They said they have both issues available.
他们说都能派上用场 －
I prefer this type. It allows you more freedom.
我更喜欢这一款,比较宽松
Quicker to get rid of when we hit the beach.
登陆后脱起来比较快
-Well? -It's on.
－怎么样？ －定下来了
Tonight, as scheduled.
今晚,照计划进行
-If the weather isn't worse. -How worse can it get?
－只要天气不更糟 －还能更糟吗？
Ike has called a high-level conference for 9:30.
艾克召集高层在九点三十开会
I am not Eisenhower. I am an assistant division commander.
我不是艾森豪威尔,我是副师长
I don't know from nothing, but he can't call it off again.
我什么都不管,但他不能再取消
Frank, turn that thing off.
弗兰克,关掉那玩意
Four thousand ships loaded for bear.
四千艘船都已装备好
Troops ready to go.
部队做好了出发准备
Eleven thousand planes on the line.
一万一千架飞机在随时待命
Eighteen thousand paratroopers. God only knows how many gliders.
加上一万八千伞兵和天知道有多少的滑翔机
Norm, relax.
诺尔,放松点
RAF says the gale can stop as suddenly as it began.
皇家空军说大风随时可能停止
So they told us yesterday and the day before.
所以他们前天昨天都这么对我们说
Look, Norm.
诺尔
We're all of us just as...
我们所有人……
...dedicated to this thing as you are, just as anxious to get going.
……都和你一样盼着开始行动
And that includes Ike.
也包括艾克
Now if he calls it off again, he knows what he's doing.
如果他再次取消行动,一定有他的理由
Of course he does. I know that.
他当然有理由,这我知道
I'm just thinking about those assault troops. 200,000 of them...
我考虑的是突击部队,一共二十万人……
...out there on those ships. They're probably seasick as hell.
……呆在船上,恐怕吐得七荤八素了
Some of those men have been on those tubs for almost three days.
有些人在“澡盆子”里呆了都快三天了
I say go.
行动吧
Go. Weather or no weather.
行动,管它天气不天气
No!
不!
A hundred on the bone! Let's go.
我押一百!来吧
-Hey, give me 50 bucks. I'm busted. -I'm not doing so good myself.
－给我五十块,我输光了 －我手气也不怎么样
Hey, lend me 50 bucks?
借我五十块行吗？
-Lend me 20 bucks? -Drop dead.
－借我二十块行吗？ －去死吧
Lend me 10?
借我十块行吗？
-Fifty on a bet. -I got it.
－五十块一注 －我有
One, two, three, four, five.
一,二,三,四,五
Fifty!
五十!
Let me hear it, let me hear it.
让我听听,让我听听
-Five and two, four and three. -Six! That's the way we go!
－五和二,四和三 －六!这样才对嘛!
Seven points in a row.It ain't logical, it just ain't logical.
一直是七点的,邪门,真邪门
-There's 100 out there. -A hundred dollars, $20.
－这把押一百块 －一百块,再加二十
Anything open?
还有要押吗？
-Forty more.
－再来四十
You got a bet.
你有赌注了
-Okay, you mother-loving-- -Just a minute. Wait a minute.
－好了,你他妈…… －等等,等一下
Here you are. Use this.
拿着,用这个
-You don't think l'd-- -I don't think anything.
－你不会以为…… －没什么以为
I just like to hear the sound when it comes out of the cup.
我只是想听到杯子发出的声音
That's it. Shake it.
就这样,摇吧
Okay. Let me see what you do with it now.  Go ahead. Shoot.
好了,让我看看你的运气,来,开吧
-What is it? -Nothing.
－是什么？ －没什么
-Seven! -That's what I wanted!
－七! －正是我想要的!
Who put this cup in the game?
是谁拿这杯子来的？
-Next shooter. Who's coming up? -I'll go $100.
－下一把,谁来掷？ －我押一百块
He's shooting 100. Who's got it?
他下一百,有谁接盘？
-Watch your side bets. -A hundred dollars.
－看好你的赌注 －一百块
You got a letter for me. Schultz, huh?
有我的信吗,舒尔茨的？
Yeah, that's it.
有,在这
Thanks, buddy.
谢谢,伙计
-How much did you take him for? -Not much. Just a hair over 2500.
－你赢了多少？ －不多,才两千五多一点
-Twenty-five hundred? -Yeah.
－两千五？ －对
Oh, man, 2500?
哦,伙计,两千五？
It's too bad you had to win it now.
现在赢钱可不太妙
What do you mean, now?
“现在”是什么意思？
Suppose we take off tonight.  What will you do with it?
要是今晚行动你拿这些有什么用？
Five I take with me to Paris to blow on the broads and wine.
五百块用来在巴黎喝酒泡马子
A thou I leave here for seed when I get back.
一千块留在这等回来再花
And the rest I send to my mother.
剩下的寄给我妈妈
Oh, man, 2500. And in Paris.
哦,伙计,两千五,还有巴黎
You always was lucky.
你总这么好运
Hey, remember that night in Fort Bragg?
记得在布拉格堡那晚吗？
I remember it.
记得
You know, I think I sneak over there and give it a big whang myself.
知道吗,我想我该过去给自己捞上一把
Why not? What's to lose?
干嘛不呢？没什么可输的嘛？
Damn it.
该死
Why did he have to mention Fort Bragg?
他干嘛提布拉格堡？
I was lucky, all right, in that crap game.
那次掷骰子我手气很好
Next day I break my leg in a jump.
第二天空降就把腿弄断了
And two months in traction.
做了两个月牵引
Twenty-five hundred dollars.
两千五百美元
That's more money I ever had in my whole life.
我这辈子从没有过这么多钱
I know.
我知道
Man, I just know.
伙计,我知道
I wonder how long it takes to lose $2500.
我倒想知道输掉两千五百美元要多久
Pint of sludge, Ted.
来一杯,特德
Oh, hello, Dave. Hey, you seen Johnny?
你好,戴夫,看到约翰尼没有？
Yes.
有
Well, where is he?
他在哪？
Come on, Dave.
说啊,戴夫
I need my boots. Johnny's borrowed them.
他借走了我的靴子
Where is he?
他在哪？
At the bottom...
躺在……
...of the Channel.
……海底
You mean...
你是说……
...he's bought it?
……他死了？
Ack-ack over Calais.
在加莱中了高射炮
He jumped clean, ut his parachute didn't open.
他跳了出来,可降落伞没能打开
That leaves just you in the squadron, Dave.
这个中队只乘下你了,戴夫
I mean, of the old 1940 mob.
我是指一九四○年那一拨老兵
What's always worried me about being one of the few...
我们这批人越变越少，正是我一直担心的事情之一
Poor old Johnny.
可怜的老约翰尼
Bad luck, it happening now.
运气真糟,在这当口
-Now, then. What's the difference? -He went through the Battle of Britain just like you!
－这当口？有什么区别？ －他和你一样捱过了不列颠战役!
And now if the big show starts tonight...
要是今晚好戏上场……
...he won't be in it.
……他就不能加入
Look, will you please shut up about him?
请不要再提他好吗？
All right, all right. I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
好的好的,对不起,对不起
You heard something about tonight?
听说今晚的事没有？
No, no. I haven't heard anything.
不,没有,什么都没听到
-What are you talking about then? -Well, it's just....
－那你刚才说的是什么？ －这个,只是…….
-Go on, go on. -I have a feeling it's on for tonight.
－继续,继续 －我有种预感就是在今晚
-That's all. -A feeling.
－如此而已 －预感
Take your feeling somewhere else.
带着你的预感去别处吧
I've got a letter to write.
我得写封信
I've had this feeling since I woke up.
我从早上起来时就有这种预感
I've had it with me all day long.
整天都有这种感觉
I can't shake it off.
无法摆脱它
It's tonight. I know it is.
就是今晚,我知道这一点
All right, it's tonight.
好吧,就是今晚
Suits me fine.
正合我意
Tonight. This afternoon. Now!
今晚,今天下午,现在!
I mean...
我是说……
...as soon as I finish this beer.
……在我喝完啤酒之后
-General, can you spare me a minute? -Come in.
－将军,你现在有空吗？ －进来吧
-Thank you. -Can I get you coffee?
－谢谢 －要咖啡吗？
-No, thanks. -I'll get some for myself.
－不用,谢谢 －我可得来点
Is it still raining?
还在下雨吗？
On and off, off and on.
下下停停,停停下下
Sometimes I wonder which side God's on.
有时我想知道上帝究竟站在哪一边
What?
什么？
I say, sometimes I wonder which side God's on.
我说,有时我想知道上帝站在哪一边
Good question.
好问题
What's on your mind, Van?
你有何想法,范？
I'm concerned about the placement of our drop zones.
我担心我们降落地点的安排
Go on.
继续说
I know this is a hell of a late date to bring up something new...
我知道现在提出新方案太晚了点……
...but you've given me a tough nut to crack.
……但你给我出了个难题
-It gets tougher every time I try. -I know, Van.
－我越想越觉得棘手 －我知道,范
Sainte-Mere-Eglise straddles the only road the Germans can use...
圣米尔伊格里斯，座落在德军唯一能用来……
...to drive into our northern flank. But it has to be taken.
……打入我军北翼的公路上,我们必须拿下
And it has to be held.
而且必须守住
That's why I gave you the job, Van.
所以我才要你去,范
-Can I use your board? -Of course.
－能用下黑板吗？ －当然
Here's the town. Heavily fortified.
这是那个镇,有重兵把守
Down here is the swamp area that the Germans have flooded.
这是沼泽地,德军已经引水淹没
And in between, four miles from the town, is our drop zone.
这二者中间，距小镇四英里处是我们的着陆点
Now, if anything goes wrong and we undershoot...
如果出了差错而提前着陆……
...we land in this flooded area and are bogged down.
……降落在沼泽地就会陷入困境
If we overshoot, we come down like clay pigeons...
如果飞过头了,就会象泥鸽一样落下……
...smack dab in the center of Sainte-Mere-Eglise.
……直接面对来自小镇的火力
That's why I gave the men training in low-level jumps near the villages.
所以我在附近的村子训练士兵低空跳伞
So I've heard.
我听说了
Got a complaint from the city council at Bexhall.
我收到了来自贝克斯荷市议会的投诉
Some of your men overshot the drop zone and landed in the town.
你的一些部下因飞过头而降落在市区
-Tied up traffic for an hour. -That's true, sir. I was with them.
－阻碍交通达一小时 －没错,头,我也在那
Sudden crosswind hit us, swept us over the treetops...
遭遇侧风,将我们吹过了树梢……
...scattered us all over the place.
……大家都给吹散了
-Where did you end up? -In the courtyard of a convent.
－你落在了哪？ －落在一家女修道院的院子里
Relax, Van. Sit down.
放松点,范,坐吧
The last few months have been a tough grind on all of us.
几个月来我们都吃尽了苦头
I hear you've been working yourself and your battalion hard.
我听说你和你的部下一直在刻苦训练
Almost without a stop.
几乎没停过
Now that we're almost at the end of the line...
现在我们就要开始行动了……
...why don't you try easing up on yourself and on the men?
……你干嘛不让自己和部下放松一下
Sometimes a battalion can be sharpened to too fine a point.
偶尔放松一下能让部队的状态更好
Sometimes a commander can too.
有时指挥官也一样
...if there's any further delay...
如果行动继续延后的话
...I request permission to submit a new placement for our drop zones.
……我请求允许重新安排降落地点
All right. Put it in writing.
行,写个报告吧
Make it official. That's your prerogative.
搞正式一点,这是你的职权
But Ike has called a final meeting for tonight at Southwick House.
不过艾克今晚要在萨维克大楼召开一个决议会 (萨维克大楼――盟军海军司令部,位于朴次茅斯城外)
If it's on, we'll get the green light by 9:30.
如果通过了,今晚九点三十就要出发
-What are the chances? -Better than 50-50.
－可能性有多大？ －超过五成
Forget everything I said. I got the best battalion in this division...
当我什么也没说,将军。我有这个师最好的一个营……
...and they're ready.
……而且已准备就绪
Here it is. The latest report.
来了,最新的报告
-It's Southwick House, sir. -Stagg here.
－萨维克大楼(盟军海军司令部)打来的,长官 －我是斯塔格
Yes, sir. The new front's moving in much faster than we thought.
是的,长官,新锋的移动比预期的要快
Yes, sir, it's definitely improving.
是的,很明显有所改善
I'll be there, sir. 9:30.
我会到的,长官,九点三十
-Would you like some more tea, sir? -Coffee, and make it black.
－还要茶吗,长官？ －咖啡吧,浓一点
Please.
谢谢
One moment, Colonel Priller.
等等,普里勒中校
Why wasn't he court-martialed?
他为什么没受军法处治？
He shot down 132 planes.
他打下了一百三十二架飞机
Hello, Pips, old boy.
你好,“匹普斯”老伙计
Don't call me "Pips, old boy."
(德国空军第二十六战斗机联队联队长约瑟夫・普里勒中校) (共击落一百零一架飞机,其中四引擎轰炸机十一架)
You were a rotten pilot when we flew in Russia.
我们在苏联时你就是个糟糕的飞行员
You're flying a desk now, but you're still a rotten pilot!
你现在升官了,可仍然是糟糕的飞行员
What's that you're saying?
你这是什么话？
I'm squatting here on this God-forsaken airfield...
我窝在这样一个见鬼的机场……
...with only two planes, two stinking crates!
……就两架飞机,纯粹是两堆破烂
Oh, sure, sure, your orders were followed!
当然,你的命令倒是生效了
Now my squadrons are God-knows-where!
可我的中队天知道在哪!
My supplies are all gone. What am I supposed to do now?
给养早就没了,我现在该做什么？
But Pips, we had to disperse our fighter squadrons. We had to!
但是“匹普斯”,我们必须分散飞行中队,必须!
Look what happened to our airstrips around the Pas-de-Calais!
看看我们加莱附近的机场遭受了什么!
The whole idea is absolutely idiotic!
这种主意真是愚蠢之极!
You move us back instead of forward!
你不让我们前进反而让我们后退
Sure, I know the weather's lousy and they probably won't invade...
当然,我知道天气恶劣,所以他们不一定会进攻……
...but what would happen if they did?
……但万一他们进攻该怎么办？
But you know I can't get there with my equipment for two days.
你该了解以我的装备至少要两天才能赶到
I tell you, you're all crazy!
老实说,你们全都疯了!
Priller has always been a hothead...
普里勒总是这么急躁……
...but let's not underestimate him.
……但不要因此而轻视他
What he says is not entirely illogical.
他的话不无道理
What's the weather report?
天气报告怎么说？
Slightly better over the Channel.
整个海峡稍有好转
I wouldn't be surprised if--
我想不会有意外,即使……
-When's the next weather report? -Tonight at 8, general.
－下次天气报告什么时候到？ －今晚八点,将军
Keep me posted on the weather.
随时向我报告天气情况
You made my dinner reservations?
替我订好晚餐座位没有？
Yes, I did, general.
订好了,将军
Cancel everything.
全部取消
-Have you got them? -Yes, sir.
－拿了没有？ －拿了,长官
Let me have them.
给我
Shoes for my wife, I had them specially made in Paris...
是送给我太太的鞋,特地在巴黎订做的……
...for her birthday, tomorrow, the sixth of June.
……为她庆祝生日,就是明天,六月六号
Please wish her a happy birthday.
代我祝她生日快乐
Thank you, Speidel.
谢谢,斯派达尔
Why didn't they attack in May? The weather was perfect....
他们干嘛不在五月进攻？ 那么理想的天气……
Tides were right, and now....
潮汐都很正常,可现在…….
An attack now would be embarrassing.
现在进攻就变得艰难了
Let's go. But I don't think we need worry.
开车, 但我们用不着担心
Is the plan ready, sir?
计划准备好了吗,长官？
Yes, yes, quite finished.
是的,计划好了
War games...
战棋推演……
...theoretical invasions.
……理论性的入侵
Rush to Rennes just to push little flags around a table.
赶去雷恩只是为了在沙盘上插些小旗罢了
Playing at war!
战争中的游戏!
Do you win or lose, sir?
您是赢是输,长官？
Have I ever lost?
我输过吗？
But general, this time you play the role of Eisenhower.
但是将军,这次您扮演的是艾森豪威尔
I win because I go against the rules.
我赢是因为我不会依常规行事
We expect them to cross at the narrowest part of the Channel...
预料中敌人将从海峡最窄之处渡海……
...and in good weather. But that's too simple, too obvious.
……而且是在好天气,但过于显而易见
I choose the widest part, in the worst weather, and attack here.
我选的是最宽之处,在最恶劣的天气,进攻此地
In Normandy.
诺曼底
And in bad weather!
在恶劣天气之中
Like now...
例如现在……
...bad weather!
……这种坏天气
Trying to pick a trend is difficult.
要作出判断很困难
From a meteorological standpoint, conditions almost resemble mid-winter.
从气象角度来说,目前的情形简直象是寒冬
And Normandy?
至于诺曼底
High winds, clouds, and some fog over the beaches.
强风,云层,以及雾气笼罩着整个海滩
However, I can say with a certain degree of safety...
不管怎样,我能完全肯定的是……
...that we can expect a brief period of fair conditions.
……将有一段短时间的好天气
Let me summarize, then.
那么换而言之
What you're promising us is a barely tolerable period of fair conditions.
你能保证的就是将有一段极为短暂的好天气
Am I right?
是不是这样？
Yes.
是的
Conditions that are far below the minimum requirements.
这样的条件远远低于最低要求
That's all I can promise.
我只能保证这些
You've done your best, Stagg. Thank you, gentlemen.
你尽力了,斯塔格,谢谢
Well, there it is.
那么,情况就是……
We've postponed the attack once already.
我们已将进攻推迟过一次
Now, either we go on the sixth, with only marginal conditions...
现在,要么趁六号的最低条件发动进攻……
...or postpone again...
……要么再次延后……
...in the hope of getting perfect conditions.
……等待理想的气候条件
What do you think, Monty?
你觉得怎样,蒙蒂？
I say, go. Go.
我选择进攻,进攻
I must remind everybody...
我必须提醒各位……
...that the American convoy for the Omaha and Utah beaches...
……负责进攻“奥马哈海滩”和“犹他海滩”的美军船队……
...they've farthest to go...
……行程最远……
...must be given the order within the next half-hour...
……必须在半小时以内向他们下令……
...if the assault is to take place on the sixth.
……如果突袭安排在六号的话
We can't keep almost a quarter of a million men on ships...
我们不能让将近二十五万人一直呆在船上……
...in embarkation areas, indefinitely.
……无限期地待命
The longer we wait, the more acute our security problem.
我们等得越久,安全隐患就越多
The next time...
下一次……
...the tides and the moon will be right....
……潮汐和月亮的正常出现…….
Not before July.
七月以前不会有
Gentlemen...
各位……
...such a postponement...
……延后如此之久……
...is too bitter to contemplate.
……是非常痛苦的选择
A brilliant plan, general. Unorthodox, but brilliant.
绝妙的计划,将军,不合常规,但堪称绝妙
Fortunately, it's only a game.
好在这只是游戏
I don't think we have much to worry about.
我觉得不用太担心
Eisenhower would never take the gamble.
艾森豪威尔从来不敢冒险
Never.
从来不
I'm quite positive we must give the order.
我十分肯定应该下令行动
I don't like it...
尽管不愿意……
...but there it is.
……但只能这样
Gentlemen...
各位……
...I don't see how we can possibly do anything else but go.
……除了行动我看不出有其他选择
Wilson speaking.
我是威尔逊
Yes, sir.
是,长官
It's on, sir. Ike's made the decision. Tonight, as scheduled!
定了,是艾克下的决定,今晚,按计划行动
Colonel Tomson speaking.
我是汤姆森上校
Thank you.
谢谢
Next stop...
下一站……
...Normandy.
……诺曼底
God help us now.
上帝保佑
Lovat here.
我是拉瓦特
Gentlemen...
各位……
...the day we've been waiting for has arrived.
……我们等待的日子终于来了
Invasion! We're on our way.
进攻!我们出发
General.
将军
The orders have been given. It's on.
收到命令了,行动
Have the battalion commanders join me in the wardroom.
召集指挥官到军官室开会
All right, sergeant.
行了,中士
You men are the eyes of our airborne Army.
你们是我们空降师的眼睛
You, the pathfinders, will have one job, and one job only:
作为伞兵引导员,你们只有一个任务
To light the drop zones for our paratroops.
为伞兵部队指明降落地点
Along with the British and Canadians you'll be the first men...
加上英国人和加拿大人,你们将是……
...to land in France.  And remember this:
……第一批登陆法国的人,记住:
When you get to Normandy...
到达诺曼底之后……
...you'll only have one friend:
……你们将只有一个朋友
God.
上帝
And this.
还有这个
This...
这个……
...is Rupert.
……是鲁珀特
Now, we are going to drop Rupert...
现在,我们要将鲁珀特……
...and a lot more like him...
……和很多类似他的同伴……
...behind the invasion area.
……空投至敌军后方
He's...
他……
...a very extraordinary fellow, Rupert.
……是个非常特别的同伴,鲁珀特
He's a sort of...
他可以说是……
...one-man army, all by himself.
……一支单兵部队
Let me show you.
让我做给你们看
Let me show you what happens when Rupert...
让你们看看鲁珀特着陆后会发生什么事
Sergeant, switch off the lights, please.
中士,请把灯关掉
All right, sergeant, that's all.
好了,中士,行了
All right, come on. Simmer down.
好的,够了,镇静
Come on, up.
行了,起来吧
It's possible that Rupert and his men will do the same thing to the Germans.
鲁珀特和他的弟兄可以对德国人做同样的事
Confuse them, make them look over their shoulders...
迷惑他们,让他们担心后方……
...and launch an attack in the wrong direction.
……向错误的方向发起攻击
Ten-hut!
立正!
-The crickets have been distributed. -So I heard.
－“蟋蟀”已经分发下去 －我听到了
At ease!
稍息!
You're as ready as we can make you.
大家已经作好了准备
This five-cent toy...
这个五分钱的玩具……
...wasn't issued to you for laughs.
……不是为了让你们发笑
It may save your life.
它也许能保住你的命
You're gonna be landing in the dark.
你们将在黑暗中着陆
On the other side of that hedgerow...
在篱笆背面的人未必和你穿着相同的制服,所以……
...one click...
……一声“咔嗒”……
...is to be answered by two clicks.
……要以两声“咔嗒”作为回应
And if you don't get that answering click...
如果你没收到回应……
...hit the dirt and open fire.
……趴下,然后开火
I repeat:
重复一次:
One click...
一声“咔嗒”……
...must be answered by two clicks.
……必须以两声“咔嗒”作为回应
Now, hang on to this gimmick.It's as important as your weapon.
现在,保管好这玩意,它和你的武器一样重要
-Do you read me? -Loud and clear, sir.
－听懂没有？ －清楚明了,头
All right. One more thing.
很好,另外要说的是
Your assignment tonight is strategic.
你们今晚的任务很关键
You can't give the enemy a break.
不能给敌人以喘息之机
Send them to hell.
送他们去地狱
That is all.
就这些
This is London calling. This is our eighth news bulletin.
伦敦广播,这是第八次新闻报道 -
Here are some personal messages.
这是一些与个人有关的口信
"Molasses tomorrow will bring forth cognac. "
“摩拉瑟斯明天将带白兰地前来”
"John has a long mustache. "
“约翰长着长胡子”
I repeat:
重复
No, not yet....
不,还不行……
Oh, my Lord!
哦,我的天
"John has a long mustache."
“约翰长着长胡子”
Make any sense to you, mac?
这表示什么,老兄？
As I said last night, they're code messages to the Resistance chaps.
我昨晚说过,是给法国抵抗组织的暗号
Obviously, one message means something to one group...
显然,信息对这个组织是这个意思……
...and another means something to another group.
……对其他组织则是其他意思
"There is a fire at the travel agency. "
“旅行社发生一起火灾”
I repeat:
重复
"Wounds my heart with a monotonous languor. "
“用单调的忧郁刺伤我的心”
The bridge, in 45 minutes.
四十五分钟后攻桥
We' ll be back.
我们会回来的
"Wounds my heart with a monotonous languor. "
“用单调的忧郁刺伤我的心”
I repeat:
重复
"There is a fire at the travel agency. "
“旅行社发生一起火灾”
The best hand I've had all night.
整晚最好的一手牌
Let me see here....
让我看看…….
Pardon me.
对不起
Pardon me, general, it's come.
对不起,将军,来了
Wait. Give that to me.
等等,给我
What's come?
什么来了？
It's the second part of the message.
信息的第二部分
-Verlaine. -Yes. The second verse.
－魏尔伦的诗 －是的,第二节
"Wounds my heart with a monotonous languor."
“用单调的忧郁刺伤我的心”
We can expect the invasion within 24 hours!
可以预计入侵将在二十四小时内发动
Put the 15th Army on full alert.
命令第十五集团军全面戒备
Thank you.
谢谢
You know, I'm too old a bunny to get very excited about all this.
这些我早已司空见惯,没什么可兴奋的
Now, where was I? Oh, yes, two spades!
我该出什么？哦,黑桃二
It's almost impossible to believe.
真是难以置信
Every dot represents a ship.
每个点代表一艘船
You got battlewagons, cruisers, destroyers, minesweepers.
有战舰,巡洋舰,驱逐舰,扫雷艇
You got assault craft of every size and every type.
有所有规格型号的攻击型船只
The biggest armada the world's ever known.
这是有史以来最大的舰队
Here.
给
You remember it.
你会记住的
Remember every bit of it.
记住每个细节
We're on the eve of a day...
这一天的前夜……
...that people will talk about long after we're dead and gone.
……我们死后人们仍将谈论很长时间
You wanna know something?
想知道一件事吗？
It gives me goose pimples just to be part of it.
单是参与其中就令我坐立不安
You could call it one of them...
你可以把它看成……
...crazy, quickie wartime marriages, you know?
……疯狂,仓促的战时婚姻之一
Met at a dance at the USO and all that...
是在劳军舞会上认识的……
...but, I mean, I took it serious.
……不过我是认真的
And so did she. We didn't do it just for kicks.
她也是,我们不单是为了找刺激
-When did you get the letter? -Week ago.
－你什么时候收到的信？ －几周前
Two weeks.
两周
Maybe I was wrong, what I wrote her.
也许我不该在信中那样写
I mean, she's a high-class model and all, and l....
我是说,她是个高级模特,而我……
I'm not the kind of guy to get married that easy.
我不是那种随随便便就结婚的人
I mean, it wasn't no joke to me.
不会拿这种事当儿戏
But oh, man, we really had some wonderful times together.
不过伙计,我们真的有过一段美好时光
And you think she's got a boyfriend?
你觉得她找了个男朋友？
Well, she never actually said so....
她从没真正说起过…….
I mean....
我是说…….
You think I was right? I mean, was I fair?
我这样对吗？我是说,公平吗？
She can't get one without your permission, right?
没你的允许她不能找别人不是吗？
You gotta give your okay.
必须要你同意
I know it's the law.
我知道这是法律
They passed it for all the Dear Johns.
它们是为军婚而制订的
Well, I guess I better be getting back to the outfit.
我想我最好还是马上归队
Good luck.
祝你好运
You too.
你也是
Who was that guy? The one you was talking to so long?
那家伙是谁？你和他聊了这么久？
I don't know, Sparrow.
我不认识,“麻雀”
I never saw him before in my life.
我以前从没见过他
Happy birthday, general, from your staff!
你的随员祝你生日快乐,将军
Thank you.
谢谢
Will you cut the cake, sir?
准备切蛋糕吗,长官？
I trust you don't expect me to eat it too!
我相信你们不会希望我吃太多
What's that?
那表示什么？
Dummkopf, that's the "V for victory" sign. Three dots and a dash.
笨蛋,那是表示胜利的信号,三短一长
Ain't you never heard Beethoven's Fifth Symphony?
没听过贝多芬的“第五交响曲”吗？
Release point coming up, Major Howard.
到着陆点了,霍华德少校
Right, prepare for landing.
好的,准备着陆
Cutting loose now.
马上脱离
Roger and out.
收到,完毕
Major Howard...
霍华德少校……
...I cannot overestimate the importance of your task.
……我不想高估你的任务的重要性
The Orne River Bridge must be captured...
但奥恩河桥必须在敌人能毁掉之前拿下
It's a vital military artery, and the enemy has prepared it for demolition.
这是至关重要的军事要道,敌人已作好炸掉它的准备
It must be taken by surprise and captured intact.
必须出其不意并且完好地拿下
Your gliders will land at night, without the benefit of ground support.
你们将在缺乏地面支持的条件下于夜间着陆
You will assault the garrison, overwhelm it...
你们要攻取该桥……
...and hold until relieved.
……并坚守直至援军到来
Hold until relieved.
坚守直至援军到来
Major Howard!
霍华德少校
There's the bridge coming up.
看到桥了
Just on our left.
就在我们左侧
Right, link your arms.
好了,大家手挽手
Brace yourselves.
打起精神
Feet up!
抬脚!
Hang on!
手挽紧!
Smoke screen. Smoke.
烟雾弹,烟雾
Up the action, bucks! Up the action, bucks!
冲上去!冲上去!
Right, Tom. Over the bridge.
好了,汤姆,上桥
Check for demolition charges!
拆除爆破装置!
Hello! Hello!
喂!喂!
Hello! Damn it! Hello!
喂!该死的!喂!
Clear.
好了
It's working!
成功了!
Hello! Hello!
喂!喂!
-Where's the doc? -On the third glider.
－医生在哪？ －第三架滑翔机上
There's no report from them.
没收到他们的报告
-Walsh. -Sir?
－沃尔什 －头？
Tom, Ruskin and Royal have had it. Take over.
汤姆他们已经得手了,你去接管
On the other end of the bridge.
在桥的另一头
-What happened to you? -Broke it on landing.
－你怎么了？ －着陆时弄断了
-Isn't the doc with you? -No, he's missing.
－医生没和你们在一起？ －他失踪了
We crashed in the river. Afraid we've got a lot of casualties.
我们落在了河里,只怕伤亡惨重
I'm all right, sir. So are the boys.
我没事,头,弟兄们一样
-Okay, carry on. -Right, sir. Come on!
－好,继续行动 －好的,头,跟我来!
Well, I'll be....
我真要…….
Hey, doc! Doc!
嘿,医生,医生
What are you doing there? That's the German side.
你在那干嘛？那边是德国人
Sir, anybody can make a mistake.
长官,谁都可能犯错
Sir?
头？
The demolition charges have been removed. It's all clear.
爆破装置已拆除,彻底安全了
Good. Corporal Smith.
很好,史密斯下士
Send out the success code words. Keep sending until acknowledged.
发送成功信号,直到收到确认信号
-John, set up HQ in that pillbox. -Right, sir.
－约翰,在碉堡设立指挥部 －好的,头
All in less than 15 minutes.
不到十五分钟就搞定了
Only a matter of time before they counterattack.
他们的反攻只是时间问题
-What about the paratroopers? -7th Para might not get here for hours.
－伞兵呢？ －第七伞兵营恐怕要数小时后才到
And Lovat and his commandos....
拉瓦特和他的突击队…….
It could be midday before they get here.
可能要午后才能到
The question is, how long can we hold?
问题就是我们能守多久了
Hold until relieved.
守至援军到来
What awful weather. It's raining again.
天气真糟,又下雨了
Thank you.
谢谢
Did you get the list?
拿到名单了吗？
General Schlieben of the 709th has already left for the war games.
七○九师师长卡尔・冯・施莱本中将已前往参加战棋推演
The commander of the 243rd left for Rennes at 1800 hours.
二四三师师长海因茨・赫尔密奇中将也于晚上六点去了雷恩
Who else?
还有呢？
Also, Zimmermann of the 352nd, 12 officers in all.
还有三五二师的齐默曼,总共十二名军官
Yes, I know.
是啊,我知道
The weather is bad, so everyone enjoys an extra night in Rennes.
天气不好,所以全都想在雷恩多享受一晚
I don't like it.
我不喜欢这样
Any of it.
一点都不
So many key officers are away at the same time.
这么多重要军官同时不在
I don't know why, but I don't like it.
不知道为什么,但我就是不喜欢
But the war games have been scheduled for a week....
但战棋推演一周前就定好了日期……
Yes, for tomorrow, not tonight.
对,是明天,不是今晚
Advise all officers who have not yet left for Rennes...
建议所有尚未前往雷恩的军官……
...to postpone their departure until tomorrow.
……推迟行程，到明天再说
May I remind you, general...
容我提醒您,将军……
...that the Allies have always landed in perfect weather conditions.
……盟军向来是在理想的天气条件下才登陆
North Africa, Sicily, ltaly....
北非,西西里,意大利…….
Yes, and always at dawn.
对,总是在黎明时分
We're 11 minutes from the green light.
我们还有十一分钟就要跳伞
Now, once more, I repeat:
现在,我再重复一次
If, for any reason, we fail to hit our drop zones...
如果意外降落到错误的地点……
...move north by east.
……就朝东北方向前进
North by east.
东北方向
The Germans have flooded large swamp areas behind the coast.
德军已经淹没了海岸后方的大面积沼泽地
Avoid them if possible.
尽量避开那
We came here to fight, not to swim.
我们是来打仗,不是来游泳
Do you read me?
听清楚没有？
Loud and clear, sir.
听清楚了,长官
How'd you make out?
结果如何？
How did you make out at the game?
你加入赌局的结果如何？
I lost.
输了
Now we're both jumping clean.
现在我们都能安全着陆了
I understand. And when will the field marshal return?
我明白,元帅将于何时返回？
I see. Oh, well.
知道了
Just a moment.
等一下
The radar report.
雷达报告
We are getting reports of strong radar interference...
我们收到报告说雷达受到强烈干扰……
...and radio reception is jammed.
……无线电接收也有阻碍
I realize this has happened before, but never this effectively!
我知道以前也有过,但从未如此严重
And the--
而且……
Call the OB West? Very well.
打给西线统帅部？好吧
Give my respects to the field marshal when he returns.
元帅返回后代我问候他
Bye, Rupert. Do your duty for God, king, and your country.
再见,鲁珀特,为上帝,国王,和你的国家效力吧
Call for reinforcements! We're under attack!
请求增援!我们遭到攻击!
Forward! Board! Fast!
往前走!上火车!快!
-Are we late? -No, but...
－我们来晚了吗？ －不,不过……
...we must hurry!
……我们得赶快!
What is it?
怎么了？
I'll go.
我去
Stop!
站住!
We said, stop!
我说站住!
Stop, or I'll shoot!
站住,不然开枪了!
What are you doing here?
你在这干什么？
I live in that farm.
我住在那个村子里
Nobody lives in that farm.
那个村子没人住
-It's abandoned. -Show me your papers.
－是空的 －出示你的证件
Hurry up!
快点!
Come with me.
跟我走
Put your bicycle there.
把脚踏车放在那
Hans!
汉斯!
Hans, where are you?
汉斯,你在哪？
-What's going on here? -Nothing!
－是怎么回事？ －没什么事!
Who is with you? I want to know!
有谁和你一起？快说!
Stop!
停下!
Stop! Stop!
停下!停下!
Good luck at the war games, general.
祝你在战棋推演中取胜,将军
Anything important?
有重要消息吗？
Communications reports difficulty in contacting our forward posts.
通信兵报告说很难和前方取得联系
The Underground again!
又是地下组织!
Some sort of rubber dummies have been dropped by parachute.
有一些用降落伞空降的橡胶假人
Rubber dummies!
橡胶假人!
Connect me with General Richter!
给我接里克特将军
We can expect commando raids and other diversionary tactics...
我们早料到将会有突袭 和其他牵制性行动……
...but I don't like this idea of dummy parachutists.
……但我不喜欢假人伞兵这种主意
Marcks speaking. Yes.
我是马克斯,对
Are you certain?
你肯定？
How many?
有多少？
What do you think of it?
你有什么看法？
Thank you, Richter.
谢谢,里克特
Paratroopers reported here, here and here!
报告说发现伞兵,这,这,还有这
Put it over there.
放在那
This is what they dropped, they explode on contact with the earth.
这就是空降的假人,碰到地面就会爆炸
In the dark, they look like soldiers.
在黑暗中看起来就象士兵
Perhaps these are what General Richter saw, not real paratroopers.
也许里克特将军看到的就是这个,而不是真的伞兵
When you create a diversion, it's for a reason.
当你组织一次佯攻时,总会有某种目的
Connect me with General Pemsel!
替我接彭塞尔将军!
Dummies...?!
假人……？!
Rubber dummies!
橡胶假人!
I agree with you, general. I'll call you back.
我同意你的看法,将军,我会再打给你
What about my call to von Rundstedt?
接通冯・龙德施泰特没有？
We haven't been able to reach him. The main lines seem to be cut.
无法取得联络,主干线似乎被切断了
Colonel Helmdach is trying to re-route the call.
正在尝试其他联络方式
They wouldn't drop dummies...
他们投下假人……
...unless it was to divert our attention from something else.
……肯定是想转移我们的注意力
In this weather?
在这种天气？
In any kind of weather!
什么天气都一样!
I must get in touch with OB West.
我必须联络西线统帅部
They're enemy paratroopers!
他们是敌人的伞兵!
Blimey, mate...
见鬼,伙计……
...you'll wake up the whole blooming German Army!
……你们会吵醒所有可恶的德国兵
Fellas!
伙计们!
I'm hung up!
我被挂住了!
-Are you all right? -Yeah.
－你没事吧？ －没事
Where have you come from?
你们是从哪来的？
Awfully sorry, old man.
非常抱歉,老头
Simply landed here by accident.
我们在这儿着陆的只能算是阴错阳差
What's that?
是谁？
Sorry I startled you. I'm trying to find my communion set.
抱歉吓到你了,我在找我的圣餐餐具
-Your what? -My communion set. I've lost it.
－你的什么？ －圣餐餐具,我把它弄丢了
Now listen, padre. We've got no time to look for--
听着神父,我们没时间来找……
I'm sure that it was here that I lost it.
我肯定是在这弄丢的
We're under fire, padre. Don't you think we ought to--?
我们处在火力之中,神父,你不觉得应该……？
You go on, my boy. Go on. I'm sure I shall only be a minute.
你走吧,我的孩子,走,我很快就能找到
Cor! Stuff a grouse.
老天!真是没办法
I've got it! I've got it!
我找到了!我找到了!
Glory be.
太好了
Now, my son, let's go about God's work this night.
现在,我的孩子,我们去完成上帝的使命
Pluskat.
我是普拉斯凯
Hello, Pluskat! Do you hear me?
喂,普拉斯凯,能听到吗？
Nothing that I've heard....
我什么都没听到…….
The usual bombing, but quite distant.
是经常有的爆炸声,但相当远
Oh, yes, I can hear it.
是的,我听到了
Well, wait a minute.
等一下
Yes, just a moment.
是的,稍等一下
Flares, but a long way up the coast.
有闪光,但离海岸很远
Yes, Cherbourg is getting hit again.
是的,瑟堡又遭到了攻击
There's probably nothing to it...
也许没什么事……
...but we have had reports of paratrooper landings.
……但是收到报告说有伞兵降落
I'll go to my bunker and take a look.
我去工事上看看
Thank you, sir.
谢谢,长官
Higher! Higher!
高一点!高一点!
Louis, open your store. We need more buckets!
路易斯,打开你的店门,我们还要些桶子
Mayor Renaud, you must come with me immediately.
雷诺镇长,你得马上跟我来
-Is it important? -Very important, Mayor Renaud.
－有要紧事吗？ －非常要紧,雷诺镇长
What's wrong, madam?
怎么了,夫人？
I was on my way to the little house outside....
我在去外边小屋的路上…….
Yes, yes, go on.
好的,继续说
Suddenly, I saw a man fall from the sky.
突然看到有个人从天而降
-A parachutist? -Yes, that's right.
－伞兵？ －是的,一点没错
He looked like a big white bird!
看起来就象只白色大鸟
-British or German? -What?
－英国人还是德国人？ －什么？
The parachutist, was he a friend or an enemy?
那个伞兵是朋友还是敌人？
I don't know. He disappeared without a word. Just "Shh!"
我不知道,他只说“嘘”,然后就不见了
-Without a word? -Just "Shh!"
－什么都没说 －只说“嘘”
Bonjour, madame...
(法语)早,女士
...je suis americain.
(法语)我是美国人
Bonjour, mademoiselle...
(法语)早,小姐
We seem to be circling.
我们似乎在兜圈子
Maybe they're having difficulty finding the drop zone.
没准他们找不到降落地点了
Okay.
好了
Go!
跳!
Go! Go! Go!
跳!跳!跳!
Paratroopers!
伞兵!
Paratroop groups.Those are paratroop groups!
伞兵部队!伞兵部队!
Anything new?
有没有新消息？
Heavy bombing over Cherbourg as usual, sir...
瑟堡那边和平时一样爆炸声不断……
...and now near Caen.
……现在接近卡昂了
The lines to Stations 6 and 8 have been cut...
第六和第八号炮位的线路被切断……
...but the direct line is open.
……但指挥线路还能接通
I'll stay for a while.
我在这呆会儿
-Would you like coffee? -Yes, thank you.
－要咖啡吗？ －好的,谢谢
For God's sakes, padre, stop that damn noise.
看在上帝份上,神父,别再弄出声音
I'm sorry, son. I'm afraid I'm lost.
抱歉,孩子,我恐怕迷路了
Well, who ain't? Now, come on.
有谁不怕？跟我来
Two clicks.
两声“咔嗒”
I heard two clicks.
我听到是两声“咔嗒”
Man...
老兄……
...am I glad to see you.
……很高兴见到你们
-You guys the 82nd? -No. This is the 101.
－你们是八十二空降师吗？ －不,是一○一空降师
101?
一○一？
Where's the 82nd?
那八十二空降师呢？
Look, bud, we don't even know where our own outfit is.
伙计,我们也不知道自己的大部队在哪
Well, somebody's shooting at somebody.
有人在攻击对方
Let's us go find this war.
我们去看看战况
Come on.
来吧
Maybe they're Limeys and ain't got no cricket.
也许是英国佬,他们没有“蟋蟀”
They must be our guys.
肯定是自己人
Okay.
好吧
No.
不
Hey.
嘿
Hey, they were Germans.
嘿,他们是德国人
Hundreds of planes have been flying to my left and right.
有数百架飞机从我们两旁飞过
Toward Caen.
是朝卡昂方向
Yes.
是的
Now over the Cherbourg peninsula. Something must be happening!
现在飞过瑟堡半岛了,一定有情况!
But what, Pluskat, what? I haven't the faintest idea.
什么情况,普拉斯凯,什么情况？ 我一点都不明白
Has anything been observed on the beaches?
海滩上发现什么情况没有？
No, nothing.
不,什么都没有
Yes, I'll let you know right away.
好的,我会随时向你报告
Of course.
当然
Are you positive that ankle's broken?
你肯定是踝骨断了？
Compound fracture, sir.
复合骨折,头
Well, put the boot back on and lace it up, tight.
把靴子穿回去,系好靴带,系紧!
Don't get mad, I didn't break it.
别发火,又不是我弄断的
And you're not walking on it.
你也不必用它走路
-You're not going to try-- -Knock it off and do as you're told.
－你不会是想…… －别再说了,照我说的做
Yes?
什么事？
A, B and C Company are scattered all over like we are.
Ａ,Ｂ,Ｃ连和我们一样全走散了
Go on.
还有呢
Major Conklin landed on a stone wall, broke his shoulder. I left him with a medic.
康克林少校落在石墙上摔断了肩膀,我把他留给卫生员了
Any contact with F Company?
联络到Ｆ连没有？
No, but they must be up ahead in the direction of Sainte-Mere-Eglise.
没有,但他们肯定在前面,圣米尔伊格里斯方向
Well, go ahead. Tie it off. Tie it off.
别停下,系好,系好
Well, here's where we are.
这是我们的位置
The northern edge of the swamp area...
在沼泽地的北端……
...five miles from our drop zone.
……离预定着陆点有五英里
Five miles.
五英里
-F Company? -No, sir.
－是Ｆ连吗？ －不,长官
And we've got scouts all over the place.
我们四处搜索过了
We even picked up a group from the 101.
找到了一○一空降师的一队弟兄
F Company were the first of the lead planes.
Ｆ连是在领航的第一架飞机上
Well, give me a hand.
扶我一把
Can I have my rifle?
把我的枪给我
Well, we'll head out this way.
我们朝这个方向走
We ought to reach high ground  and open country by daybreak.
天亮时我们应该能到达高地或者开阔地
All right. Have the men spread out...
好了,让大家分散开来……
...pick up any stragglers they can find.
……沿途召集走散的弟兄
-Pass the word. -Right, sir.
－把话传下去 －是,长官
All right, men, spread out. Pick up stragglers you see.
大家分散开,聚拢掉队的弟兄
Pass the word down.
把话传下去
All right...
好了……
...Iet's go.
……我们出发
From the latest reports, this is how I see it:
根据最新的报告,我的看法是……
American paratroopers have landed....
美军伞兵已经降落在…….
...here.
……这
British paratroopers here.
英军伞兵在这
The invasion....
将会进攻…….
...here.
……这
Yes. Thank you, Pemsel.
是的,谢谢,彭塞尔
General Pemsel is convinced that this is the invasion.
彭塞尔将军确信这是入侵
I do not agree with him. This is my conclusion:
我不同意,我的看法是……
Normandy is the objective of a diversionary attack.
诺曼底只是牵制性攻击的目标
A diversionary attack, Blumentritt.
是牵制性攻击,布鲁门特里特
It's not the main attack. That will come at the Pas-de-Calais...
不是主要攻击目标,主目标是加莱……
...where it was always expected.
……早就预料到的地点
Where we always expected it.
那是我们预料的地点
But we can't take any chances.
但我们不能掉以轻心
I want the reserve panzers moved up at once!
立刻出动装甲预备队
We need approval from the Fuhrer's headquarters.
必须经过元首统帅部的同意
They wouldn't dare refuse me!
他们不敢拒绝我的要求
Call the Fuhrer's headquarters and insist.
打电话给元首统帅部强调这一点
Insist that the panzers be released to me immediately!
强调装甲部队要交由我直接指挥
An invasion of Normandy would be against all military logic.
进攻诺曼底悖离了军事常规
It would really be against all logic.
实在是悖离所有常规
Well, that about covers it, gentlemen.
大概就是这些了,各位
Most of you have had your feet wet before:
你们大部分以前有过登陆经验
Dunkirk, Dieppe, Norway.
敦克尔克,迪耶普,挪威
And we know what it means to be driven into the sea.
大家都知道被赶下海是指什么
In a few hours we're going back from the sea.
几小时后我们要从海上杀回去
And this time we're going to stay.
这次我们要站住脚
There's no time for any sob stuff about...
没有时间来为英格兰,家园,以及美女而伤感
Remember, our people have had a rough time for four and a half years.
记住,我们的同胞已经受苦受难四年半了
They've earned the final victory.
他们应该赢得最后的胜利
Let's give it to them.
让我们来实现它
And to our French comrades in arms, I say:
对于军中的法国战友,我要说……
Good luck.
祝你们好运
Tomorrow morning, we'll take them.
明早,我们要打败他们
Come in, Teddy. That will be all, sergeant.
请进,泰迪,　　 就这样吧,中士 -
Did you have to put it in writing?
你一定要写进报告吗？
I knew you wouldn't let me go unless I did.
不这样你就不会让我去
You're putting me on the spot.
你这是给我出难题
-I didn't mean to, Tubby. -The hell you didn't.
－我不是有意的,塔比 －不是才怪
You put that request in writing, made it official.
你都将请求写进了正式报告
You're the assistant division commander.
你可是副师长
And that's why I'm supposed to go ashore in the first wave.
所以我应该第一波上岸
That's where I'm supposed to be.  You know that.
我应该去那,你知道的
You're important to this operation.
你对这次行动很重要
We can't have you knocked off on the first day.
我们不能在第一天就失去你
But that's not the real reason.
可那不是真正的理由
Isn't it because my father was president of the United States?
是不是因为我父亲是美国总统？
And a great president.
而且是了不起的总统
And a great soldier.
也是了不起的军人
He led the charge of the Rough Riders up San Juan Hill.
他曾带领“铁骑兵”攻下了圣胡安山
So now you've got to be the first man ashore on Utah Beach.
所以现在你想成为第一个登上“犹他海滩”的人
But that's where I'm supposed to be, Tubby. That's my job.
可那是我应该去的地方,这是我的职责
Also, I've been there side by side with the men all through training.
而且我和部下一起经历过所有训练
They're used to seeing me there. They have a right to expect me there.
他们习惯看到我在场,也有权利期待我在场
President's son or not.
不管是不是总统的儿子
Is my request denied?
我的请求被拒绝了？
No, you know it's not.
不,你知道不会的
Request reluctantly approved.
被很不情愿地批准了
Thanks, Tubby.
谢谢,塔比
Thanks a lot.
非常感谢
Say...
那么……
...how's that arthritis of yours?
……你的关节炎怎么样了？
Arthritis?
关节炎？
Haven't had a touch in months.
好几个月没发作了
Glad to hear it.
真是个好消息
The street...
街道……
...the bridge...
……桥……
...the hotel...
……旅馆……
...the casino.
……赌场
That's it, gentlemen.
就是这样,各位
One more thing....
另外……
You have been fighting everywhere for four years...
四年来你们转战各方……
...in Abyssinia, Libya, Egypt, Crete....
……阿比西尼亚,利比亚,埃及,克里特岛……
But this time you are going to fight on French soil...
但这次你们是在法国的领土上作战……
...in our fields...
……是在我们的土地……
...in our villages...
……我们的乡村……
...under the eyes of our own people.
……我们同胞的眼皮底下
I can't wake the Fuhrer on the strength of contradictory reports.
我可不能为这自相矛盾的报告叫醒元首 (阿尔弗雷德・约德尔陆军上将) (德国武装部队最高统帅部作战部部长)
He was up till four. He took a sedative and then retired.
他吃过镇静剂在睡觉,要四点起床
I won't wake him for these reports.
我不能为这些报告吵醒他
First we hear that the paratroopers are shot down plane crews.
最初的报告说伞兵是被击落飞机上的机组人员
Next they are identified as mechanical dummies.
然后又被说成是橡胶假人
If these reports are true and paratroopers have landed...
即使报告都是真的而且伞兵已经着陆……
...it can only be a commando raid.
……也可能只是一次突袭而已
Is that a sufficient reason to send the panzers to the coast?
这种理由足以派装甲部队前往海岸吗？
I will submit all reports to the Fuhrer as soon as he awakens.
元首醒后我会尽快将这些报告提交给他
I understand.
明白了
Jodl has turned us down.
约德尔拒绝了请求
He will not release the panzers without the Fuhrer's approval...
没有元首的批准，他不会将装甲部队交给我们……
...and the Fuhrer is still asleep!
……而元首还在睡觉!
Will you tell von Rundstedt?
要通知冯・龙德施泰特吗？
No, not now....
不,暂时不用…….
Not now.
暂时不用
Thank you, gentlemen.
谢谢,各位
Sit down.
坐吧
This is history.
这是历史性的
We are living a historical moment.
我们正处在一个历史性的时刻，我们要输掉这场战争了……
...because the glorious Fuhrer has taken a sleeping pill...
……就因为伟大的元首吃了一颗安眠药……
...and is not to be awakened.
……所以不能被吵醒
It's unbelievable.
真是难以置信
Think of it, Kurt.
想想这一刻,库尔特
Don't ever forget it.
永远别忘了这一刻
We are witnessing something...
我们正在见证一件事……
...which historians will always say is completely improbable...
……历史学家会一直说这绝无可能……
...and yet it is true.
……但却千真万确
The Fuhrer is not to be awakened!
元首不能被吵醒!
I sometimes wonder whose side God is on.
有时我真想知道上帝是站在哪一边
Can l...
要我……
...bring you anything, sir?
……为您拿点什么来吗？
In my room there is a bottle of excellent cognac...
我房间里有一瓶上等的干邑白兰地……
...Napoleon, unopened.
……“拿破仑”,还没开过
I was even saving it for a fitting occasion.
我本想留到一个合适的场合再开
This isn't exactly the right occasion, but get it anyway.
现在算不上合适的场合,可还是拿来再说吧
Daylight at last.
总算天亮了
A whole night wasted again!
又浪费了一整夜!
Where's my dog?
我的狗呢？
He was here a minute ago.
刚才还在这呢
Let's have one last look.
最后再看一下
Nothing.
什么都没有
Not even a seagull....
连只海鸥都没……
My God!
我的天!
The invasion.
入侵
They're coming!
他们来了!
Everyone to your posts!
各就各位!
It's the invasion!  There must be 5000 ships out there!
是入侵!海上至少有五千艘船!
Get hold of yourself, Pluskat.
镇静一点,普拉斯凯
The enemy doesn't have even half that many.
敌军的船只连那一半都不到
Well, damn it!  Come and see for yourself, you fool!
该死的,自己过来看看吧,你这白痴!
It's amazing.
太惊人了
It's beyond belief.
真不敢相信
My dear Pluskat, where are these ships heading?
亲爱的普拉斯凯,那些船在朝哪开？
Straight for me!
冲我这来了!
General, in exactly two minutes...
将军,两分钟之后……
...the fleet will open fire.
……舰队就将开火
Your attention, please. The admiral has an announcement.
请注意,将军将发表讲话
Soon we will have the honor to be engaged in battle.
我们很快将光荣地投身于战斗之中
To drive the enemy out, we must fire on our homeland.
为了赶走敌人,我们不得不向自己的领土开火
This is the price of liberty.
这是自由的代价
Long live France!
法兰西万岁!
There he goes, right on time, as usual.
他去了,很准时,和往常一样
They're landing! They're coming! They're coming!
他们要上岸了!他们来了!他们来了!
I'm not crazy. Look, they're landing!
我没疯,看,他们快上岸了!
The Americans, the English and the French!
美国人,英国人,还有法国人!
You must be deaf! Can't you...?
你一定是聋了!难道……？
Damn it, can't you hear it for yourself?
该死的,难道你没听见吗？
We're under fire. Yes, under fire!
我们正遭到攻击! 是的,遭到攻击!
Those 5000 ships you say the Allies haven't got...
你说盟军弄不到的那五千艘船……
...well, they've got them!
……他们弄到了!
It's wonderful!
真是太好了!
Yes? What is it now?
喂？又有什么事？
Listen to me, Pips.
听我说,“匹普斯”
The invasion has started!  Put yourself on alert at once!
入侵已经开始!马上进入戒备状态!
What the hell can I do with only two planes?
就凭两架飞机我能干什么？
Where are the others, you idiots?!
其他飞机在哪？你这白痴!
Priller, that's an order!  Get ready at once! Understand?
普里勒,这是命令!马上准备!明白了吗？
If it isn't too much trouble...
如果不是太麻烦的话……
...would you tell me where the invasion is?
……能告诉我入侵地点是在哪吗？
What? Normandy! How delightful!
什么？诺曼底!真是太妙了!
Thanks, my faithful Hans. That's the end for us! So long!
谢了,我忠实的汉斯,这下我们完了!永别了!
It's getting very difficult  to get any sleep around here.
在这想睡个好觉真是太难了
Your prospects for a long sleep are excellent. The invasion has begun.
你准备好长眠不醒吧,入侵已经开始了
Normandy. We're flying there, the two of us.
诺曼底,我们要飞往那,我们俩
Nobody else is left.
没有其他人
I don't think we're coming back.
我们恐怕是回不来了
Move out! Move out!
开始行动!开始行动!
The shelling has stopped.
轰炸已经停止
Landing craft approaching.
登陆艇正在接近
Return to headquarters. Direct your troops from there!
回到你的指挥部,到那里指挥你的部队!
Landing craft approaching the coast!
登陆艇正在接近海岸!
Those French bastards!
那些法国混蛋!
Sergeant!
中士!
Send this to headquarters by courier.
派人把这个送到总部去
No! Take it yourself. Tell them our lines are cut!
不!你亲自去,告诉他们线路被切断了
Gentlemen, come here please.
各位,请过来
Attack!
准备攻击!
Fast!
快!
Take your positions!
各就各位!
Don't let them get too close!
别让他们靠得太近!
Fast!
快!
Attack!
准备攻击!
There it is, men.  Omaha Beach, dead ahead.
就是那,弟兄们,“奥马哈海滩”,死神就在前边
Lock on the target!
瞄准目标!
Stand by!
准备行动!
Get off of the beach!
快离开海滩!
Let's go!
我们走!
Come on, move up!
快,前进!
Hello, general, sir.
你好,将军先生
-Are you all right, boy? -Yes, sir.
－你没事吧,小子？ －没事,长官
Don't you think you better go back and get your rifle?
你不觉得回去拿上你的枪比较好吗？
Out there, sir?
去那吗,长官？
You're almost sure to need it before this day is over.
今天结束以前你肯定用得着它
Yes, sir.
是,长官
Come on! Move on up! Let's go.
快!前进!前进
Medic! Medic!
医生!医生!
General, first reports from Omaha, sir.
将军,“奥马哈海滩”来的第一份报告
"Assault teams have landed.
“突击部队已经登陆
No direct radio contact, but destroyers report...
“尚未取得电台联络,但是驱逐舰报告说……
...first and second waves appear pinned down on the beach.
“……第一和第二波似乎被困在海滩上
Concentrated artillery and mortar fire.
“遭到炮兵和迫击炮集中攻击
Third wave floundering." Heavy casualties, sir.
“第三波前进困难”   伤亡惨重,长官
When the mortars and machine guns are silenced...
等迫击炮和机枪安静下来之后……
...have the battalion commanders join me over there.
……要各单位指挥官在那和我碰头
Okay.
明白
Hang on to that map case, Eddie.
把地图拿好,艾迪
I made it.
我成功了
Hey, I made it.
嘿,我成功了
Did you see me get those two guys?
看到我撂倒那两个家伙没有？
Hey, sergeant?
嘿,中士？
Sergeant?
中士？
As best as I can figure it, this is the wrong beach.
据我估计,这不是正确的地点
We're a mile and a quarter south of where we were supposed to land.
我们是在预计登陆点以南一又四份之一英里处
We should be up there.
我们应该在那边上岸
Control boat must've been confused by the naval bombardment smoke.
指挥船一定是被海面的炮火烟雾弄糊涂了
I agree with you, but what will we do now?
我同意,那现在该怎么办？
Reinforcements and heavy equipment will approach in a very few minutes.
援军和重型武器几分钟内就会到
-I know, I know. -What if they land at the right beach?
－我知道,我知道 －如果他们是在正确地点登陆呢？
The reinforcements will have to follow us wherever we are.
不管我们在哪,援兵都得跟着我们
We're starting the war from right here.
我们就从这儿开始进攻
-Head inland. We're going inland. -Okay, let's go.
－我们向内陆前进 －好的,出发
Follow me. Do everything I do!
跟紧我,照我的样子做!
All right. Let's go!
好了,出发!
Head for home!
回家了!
The Luftwaffe has had its great moment!
这是德国空军历史上最美好的一刻!
Stand by to beach.
准备抢滩
Duncan, take care of that strongpoint.
邓肯,小心那个据点
Any minute now. Stand by!
随时准备行动!
Let's give it them back for Dunkirk!
让我们为敦克尔克还以颜色!
You hear that? Dunkirk. Do you hear it, Clough?
敦克尔克,你听到没有,克拉夫？
Sure he was at school at the time.
那会儿他还乳臭未干呢
Come on, you bums!
来吧,你们这些废物!
Come out, you dirty slobs! Flanagan's back!
出来,你们这些下流坯! 弗拉纳根回来了!
The evil of it all. Drowning a man before he fights.
还没打仗就给淹死,那可太不幸了
Oh, come on!
哦,来吧!
Keep those vehicles moving!
车辆继续前进!
MP, chase out those cyclists.
宪兵,跟上那些骑自行车的
Get off the beach!
(英国皇家海军海滩指挥官 科林・莫德海军上校)
Move inland!
向内陆前进!
Come on, you lot!
你们快点!
Hurry it up.
赶快
Never mind the blathering!
别在这闲聊!
We must put these down somewhere.
我们要把装备都安顿好
The sooner you get off the beach...
你们越早离开海滩……
...the sooner they'll stop this blasted shelling.
……他们就会越早停止这可恶的炮击
It's very bad for the dog!
炮击会吓着我的狗!
Down, Winston, down!
镇静,温斯顿,镇静!
Beach Master Sword, Section 2-A.
“剑海滩”海滩指挥官,２－Ａ区
Third wave ashore on time. No obstruction to follow-up.
第三波已准时登陆,后续行动未受阻碍
Standing by.
待命中
Get going!
开始行动!
For heaven's sake, get that carrier off the beach!
看在上帝的份上,把它弄出海滩!
I was told I could transmit a newsflash on your radio.
我听说可以用你的无线电发个简报
If you can't drive it, carry it!
如果不能开走,就把它搬走!
You were saying?
你说什么？
I was told I could transmit a newsflash on your--
有人说可以用你的无线电……
My dear fellow, I don't want to appear uncooperative--
亲爱的伙计,我不想显得不合作……
Yes, I know all about the power of the press.
不错,我知道媒体的力量
But this line happens to be rather busy! Come on!
但这条线得忙更重要的事!快点!
Down, Winston. Down, Winston.
镇静,温斯顿,镇静,温斯顿
What did he say?
他怎么说？
The answer is no.
他说不行
We have to use the damn pigeons.
只好用该死的鸽子了
I've got these ready.
好在我早有准备
Here, clip this on.
来,绑上去吧
They're going the wrong way.
它们飞错了方向
Not toward the Germans, you idiots!
那边是德国人,白痴!
The other way! The other way!
是这边!是这边!
Damned traitors!
该死的叛徒!
-Hold it. -Can't you get your finger out?
－牵着它 －你就不能把你的手指拿出来手吗？
-What's the matter? -Engine won't start, sir.
－怎么回事？ －引擎无法启动,长官
Full of seawater, I think.
我想是进了海水
My old grandmother used to say...
我的老祖母经常说……
...anything mechanical, give it a good bash.
……机械有什么问题就狠狠揍它
Try it now.
现在试试
Thank you, sir.
谢谢,长官
Off you go. Good luck.
走吧,祝你们好运
I'm sure that got it out.
这一下可真有用
That's what I call a hell of a man!
这就是我说的厉害角色!
Aye, I like his dog too.
我也喜欢他的狗
Don't stand there yapping!
别在那废话了!
This isn't Hyde Park Corner! The war's over there!
这可不是海德公园!是战场!
Come along!
跟上!
Come on!
快!
-Thank you. -Everything's going according to plan.
－谢谢 －一切都很顺利
Stand by to move. Millin, "Blue Bonnet."
等待行动命令,米林,“蓝色无边帽”
What in God's name...?
搞什么鬼……？
Oh, my friends. What a day! What a day!
我的朋友,多么美好的一天!
Welcome to France. Welcome to Colleville!
欢迎来到法国!欢迎来到高利维尼苏!
Most kind of you. Very nice to meet you--
你太好了,真是幸会……
Look at this. I kept it for you all.
看,我一直留着这个
But I don't think there will be enough for everyone.
不过恐怕不够大家喝的
Perhaps next time. We have a previous engagement: the war!
也许下次吧,我们还另有预约:打仗!
Mustn't lose that champagne!
不必浪费香槟了!
All right, men, fall in! Millin, "Blue Bonnet."
好了,大家集合! 米林,“蓝色无边帽”
Goodbye.
再见
Thank you, boys! Thank you!
谢谢,小伙子们!谢谢!
Long live France! Long live the Allies!
法兰西万岁!盟军万岁!
If you ask me, Flanagan...
要我说的话……
...there's a lot of very peculiar blokes on this beach.
……这海滩上真有不少古怪的家伙
Welcome!
欢迎!
Welcome to you all!
欢迎大家!
Thank you, dear, they're lovely!
谢谢,亲爱的,这鞋真漂亮!
Better try them on first.
最好先穿上试试
Rommel speaking.
我是隆美尔
Good morning.
早
What?
什么？
What!
什么!
Where?
哪？
Normandy!
诺曼底!
Have they a foothold already?
他们已经登陆了吗？
They must be thrown back!
必须阻止他们!
What about the panzer reserves?
装甲预备队呢？
Did von Rundstedt obtain their release from the Fuhrer?
冯・龙德施泰特从元首那获取指挥权没有？
Normandy, Normandy.
诺曼底,诺曼底
How stupid of me!
我真是愚蠢!
Stupid.
愚蠢
There it is.
就是那
You mean to tell me that's all we gotta climb?
你是说我们得从那爬上去吗？
They're not as high as the practice ones.
还没有训练爬的那么高
They wasn't shooting at us then.
训练时可没有炮火
Why can't the Air Force or Navy do this job?
为什么不让空军或是海军来干？
The big guns in bunkers behind the cliff can't be seen from the air.
从空中看不到悬崖后面掩体内的大炮
We knock them out or they'll murder our guys on the beach.
不干掉它,它就会干掉我们海滩上的弟兄
Yeah, well, if you ask me...
是啊,要我说的话……
...three grandmothers with brooms could sweep us off there...
……三个老太婆用扫帚就能把我们一扫光
...like flies off of a sugar cake.
……就象从甜饼上轰走苍蝇一样
That's it, the one we're after.
就是它,我们要找的目标
It's empty.
是空的
The Air Force and Navy really plastered this baby.
空军和海军确实给了他们好看
But I don't get--
可我没明白……
The guns.
这些炮
There ain't no mounts.
都没有架好
They've never even been installed.
根本就还没有安装过
You mean...
你是说……
...we come up all this way...
……我们费了这么大的劲……
...for nothing?
……却只是一场徒劳？
Don't worry, sarge, you'll be all right.
别担心,你不会有事
Medic! Medic!
医生!医生!
"Bitte!", "Bitte!"
(德语) “请别!”, “请别!”
I wonder what "Bitte, Bitte" means.
他叽哩咕噜的在说什么？
What the hell are you wearing a life preserver for?
你穿着救生衣搞什么鬼？
I can't swim.
我不会游泳
Normandy. It really is Normandy.
诺曼底,真的是诺曼底
This is madness, madness, sheer madness!
真是疯狂,疯狂,纯粹是疯狂!
What is it?
什么事？
I just talked to General Jodl, the Fuhrer is awake.
我刚和约德尔将军通过话,元首已经醒了
I don't care if he's awake or not! What about the reserve panzers?
我才不在乎他醒没醒!装甲预备队的事怎么样？
The Fuhrer went into one of his tantrums...
元首在大发雷霆……
...and no one dared bring up the subject.
……所以没人敢提任何事
They're still held in reserve!
那就是还处于预备状态!
Yes, field marshal.
是的,元帅
Sir, if you would call the Fuhrer yourself...
长官,如果你亲自打给元首……
...I am convinced he would respect your views.
……我相信他会尊重你的看法
Call him?
打给他？
Call that Bohemian corporal?!
打给那个波希米亚下士？!
Crawl on my knees to him?!
要我向他奴颜卑膝？!
No! It is out of the question!
不!连想都不要想!
"Wounds my heart with a monotonous languor."
“用单调的忧郁刺伤我的心”
What's that?
什么意思？
Nothing, nothing of importance.
没什么,已经没有意义了
Here, let me help you.
来,我来帮你
You all right, Tom?  Come on, they're up there.
你还好吧,汤姆？快,他们在上边
-Sir. -Well?
－头 －怎么？
Mr. Smith says to tell you he's stood his men too.
史密斯要我转告你,他的人已准备好
The Jerries are moving up into the woods...
德军带着机枪和迫击炮推进到了树林里
-Tell the men to stand firm! -Tell the chaps--
－要弟兄们做好准备! －告诉弟兄们……
Tell them to expect another counterattack, a heavy one.
准备应付敌人下一轮猛烈反攻
-Here you are, mate. -Ta.
－拿着,伙计 －谢谢
-What's the matter? -Listen.
－什么事？ －听
I thought I heard bagpipes.
我听到了风笛声
Don't be daft!
别傻了!
I told you I heard bagpipes! It's the reinforcements.
我告诉你听到了风笛声!是援兵
It's Lovat!
是拉瓦特!
Come on!
快!
-Sorry I'm late. -Better than never, sir.
－抱歉来晚了 －比不来要好
Glad to see you, Shimmy.
真高兴见到你,希米
You boys are right on target. What's the situation?
你们正好被当成了靶子,情况如何？
Jerry's regrouping in the woods, about a mile.
德军在一英里外的树林中重新部署
With mortars and heavy machine guns.
有迫击炮和重机枪
Numbers?
有多少？
No idea, Shimmy, but they seem to be moving forward in force.
不知道,希米,但似乎正在集结更多兵力
In that case, we won't wait.
那样的话,我们就更不能等了
We'd better get moving.
最好还是行动
All right, we're going across.
好了,我们要穿过去
-Millin! -Sir?
－米林! －是？
"Black Bear," sir.
吹“黑熊”
All right, come on.
好了,来吧
Everybody up!
都起来!
On your feet!
出发!
There he goes. He's at it again.
是他,他又在吹了
Ever hear such a bleeding racket in all your life?
你这辈子听过这么难听的声音吗？
Yeah, it takes an Irishman to play the pipes.
没错,爱尔兰人吹风笛就是这样
Hold until relieved.
坚守至援兵到来
North by east, north by east. Sainte-Mere-Eglise is that way.
北偏东方向,北偏东方向,圣米尔伊格里斯在这边
Somebody turned that sign around.
有人移动过路标
Doesn't anybody in this outfit look at a compass besides me?
队里除了我就没人看一下指南针吗？
Hey, you guys!
嘿,伙计们
Over here! Over here!
过来!过来!
Over here, on the double.
过来,跑步!
-Where you taking that? -We don't know, sir.
－要把它弄到哪去？ －不知道,长官
We took the wrong road.
我们走错了路
What do you got in here, ammo?
里面有什么？弹药吗？
Yes, sir.
是的,长官
-You 82nd? -No, sir, 101.
－你们是八十二空降师？ －不,长官,是一○一空降师
Well, you're in the 82nd now.
现在你们归八十二空降师了
-But, sir, we're-- -But what?
－可是长官…… －可是什么？
Nothing, sir.
没什么,长官
All right, move out.
好了,出发
-Knock that sign down! -Yes, sir.
－把路标拔掉! －是,长官
-Something's moving up there, colonel. -Hit the dirt! Take cover.
－上面有东西移动,中校 －卧倒!掩蔽
Lieutenant Sheen, sir, A Company.
是Ａ连的西恩中尉,头
Colonel, it's me!
中校,是我!
-Where did you come from? -Sainte-Mere-Eglise.
－你从哪来？ －圣米尔伊格里斯
We hold the main road and north side of the square.
我们控制了主要道路和广场北侧
The Germans have a battery on the other side of the town...
德军有一个炮兵连在镇子的另一边……
-...and command the countryside. -And Major Lance?
－……控制着乡村地区 －兰斯少校呢？
-Holed up in a building in the square. -F Company?
－埋伏在广场的一幢建筑里 －Ｆ连呢？
They overshot the drop zone and landed in the middle of the town.
他们飞过了空降地点,降落到了镇中心
Go on.
继续说
It was a nightmare, sir. A slaughter.
那是场恶梦,一场屠杀
They were mowed down before they hit the ground.
在着地之前就被全歼了
Major Lance sent me to try and contact you, sir.
兰斯少校派我来和你联络
He wants your permission to pull back and regroup outside of town.
他想要你批准撤退,然后在镇外重新部署
No, damn it. We came here to take Sainte-Mere-Eglise.
不,该死的,我们要拿下圣米尔伊格里斯
We're gonna take it and hold it.
要拿下并守住它
Follow the lieutenant, gentlemen.
跟着中尉,弟兄们
-Sir. -Thank you.
－长官 －谢谢
British and Canadians advancing steadily from Sword, Gold, and Juno.
英,加两军正从"剑海滩","金海滩"和"朱诺海滩"稳步推进
Anything from Omaha?
“奥马哈海滩”有消息吗？
Nothing since the first message: heavy fighting, heavy casualties.
只收到了第一条消息:激战,伤亡惨重
Sir.
长官
Omaha?
“奥马哈海滩”来的？
No.
不是
I can't understand why Jerry hasn't brought his heavy armor into play.
真搞不懂德军为什么不投入重型装甲部队
All the panzer divisions except the 21st...
除了二十一装甲师,其余装甲师……
...seem to be sitting it out in the rear.
……似乎都远在后方
Sir.
长官
"French commandos driving inland from Sword...
“法军突击队从‘剑海滩’直驱内陆……
...have reached the outskirts of Ouistreham."
……已到达乌伊斯特勒昂郊外”
Ouistreham.
乌伊斯特勒昂
Fall back!
撤退!
Take cover!
掩蔽!
Tank support! We must have tank support!
坦克支援!我们需要坦克支援!
Hello, Bastille. Hello, Batille. This is Windsor. Come on, Bastille!
呼叫“巴士底”,呼叫“巴士底”, 我是“温莎”,请回答,“巴士底”!
Fire!
开火!
Attention!
注意!
Hello, Bastille. Hello, Batille. This is Windsor. Come on, Bastille!
呼叫“巴士底”,呼叫“巴士底”, 我是“温莎”,请回答,“巴士底”!
I can't get them!
无法取得联络!
Keep trying! We must have support!
继续试!我们必须有支援!
Hold your positions. I'm going for a tank!
坚守岗位,我去找辆坦克!
Give us as much cover as you can!
尽可能给我们掩护!
The bridge, right!
桥,右侧!
Fire!
开火!
Try for the cannon!
干掉那门大炮!
Get the wounded out of here!
把伤员弄出去!
Go back!
回去!
Get out of here!
离开这!
No! Go back!
不!回去!
You can't stay here!
你们不能留在这!
I am Mother Superior of the convent.
我是修道院的院长嬷嬷
The Sisters are qualified nurses.
这些修女都是合格的护士
But madame-- I mean, Mother, we're in the middle of a battle!
可是夫人…… 我是说,嬷嬷,我们正在打仗!
Excuse me. Take care of the wounded.
失陪,照顾伤员
It's a tank!
是坦克!
It's Kieffer!
是基佛!
In the other direction!
在另一边!
Clear away the debris! Hurry!
清除碎石!快!
But where is the Luftwaffe?!
我们的空军在哪？!
-I'm trying. -Yeah, yeah, you're trying.
－我正在联系 －好的,好的,快找吧
The British troops have a beachhead here. They are moving inland.
英军攻下了一个滩头阵地,正向内陆挺进
The Americans hold Ste-Mere-Eglise and have cut the highway.
美军占领了圣米尔伊格里斯,并切断了公路
We control this center section.
我们控制着中央地带
The Americans have landed but their attack has bogged down.
美军虽已登陆,但他们被我军困住了
Rommel is right.
隆美尔说得对
If we can hold them on the beaches...
如果我们能将他们困在海滩上……
...the invasion will collapse.
……入侵就会落空
Medic!
医生!
That thing still work?
这玩意还能用吗？
Yes, sir, now and then.
是的,长官,偶尔能用
-Anything from the other beaches? -Not directly.
－有没有其他滩头的消息？ －无法直接联络
A while ago the sergeant picked up some flashes from the destroyers.
有人收到从驱逐舰发出的闪光信号
The 4th Division is off Utah Beach and moving inland.
第四师已离开“犹他海滩”向内陆挺进
Inland?
内陆？
-What about the 1st Division? -They're hung up, sir.
－第一师呢？ －他们被困住了,长官
Like we are.
和我们一样
Move out.
行动
Medic!
医生!
-What do you think? -Think?
－你有什么想法？ －想法？
We must have close to 1000 casualties up to now.
我们现在死伤至少有一千人
Do you want me to have the ships start picking us up?
要联络船只来接我们吗？
-You think it's that bad? -I don't see what else to do.
－你认为有这样糟？ －我看不出有其他选择
We can't get up this hill.
我们无法登上山头
If we don't get off this beach, we won't have any division left.
如果不能离开海滩,我们会全军覆没
What?
什么？
These are our men, Tom.
这是我们的部下,汤姆
You think we brought them in so some die and ask the rest to turn tail?
带他们来难道是为了送死,然后让剩下的人逃跑吗？
Hell, no. We're gonna get up that hill.
见鬼,不,我们要拿下那个山头
Find me somebody to speak for the Rangers.
派人去把“轻骑兵”(突击队)给我找来
Back down the beach on the right there's a gully.
海滩背面右侧有一条溪谷
With a heavily defended roadblock and machine gun nests on both sides.
有一支重兵把守,两侧有机枪驻守
-If we can blow our way through-- -We've hit it three times.
－如果我们能杀开一条路…… －试过三次了
-We didn't get close. -Three times isn't enough.
－根本无法接近 －三次不算多
We're gonna hit it again. Can you find me some engineers?
我们要再试,能找些工兵来吗？
They're all around you!
到处都是!
I mean engineers with equipment still working.
我是指带有可用装备的工兵
Then I shouldn't radio the ships?
不用和船只联络吗？
No, damn it!
不用,该死的!
We need bangalore torpedoes, bazookas, mortars, wire cutters...
我们需要爆破筒,火箭筒,迫击炮,剪钳……
...and every man that can stand. Pass the word, will you?
……和所有还能行动的人,传话下去行吗？
Okay, Norm.
好的,诺尔
Now listen to me, all of you.
大家都给我听着
You guys got to snap out of it.
你们要打起精神
We're getting off of here, and we're going inland.
我们要离开这向内陆前进
What about weapons, general?  My men lost everything.
武器呢？将军,我的弟兄手无寸铁了
They gotta have something to fight with.
他们得有装备才行
Strip the dead and the wounded.
解除死伤人员的武装
Pick up anything that'll shoot.
凡是可用的武器都带上
I don't have to tell you the score, you all know it.
用不着我说,你们都清楚
Only two kinds of people are gonna stay on this beach:
只有两种人能留在海滩上
Those that are already dead and those that will die. Get off your butts!
已经死掉的和将会死掉的,都给我起来!
You guys are the fighting 29th!
你们是身经百战的二十九师!
I've looked at the naval reports.
我看过海军的报告
Yes?
怎么样？
According to reports from the offshore destroyers, Omaha is a shambles.
据驱逐舰传来的报告说,“奥马哈海滩”凶多吉少
There's no evidence-- To quote the report exactly:
没有迹象……  报告原文是:
"There is no evidence of any movement that can be observed off the beach."
“海滩上观察不到有任何活动的迹象”
I'd better have a look through these.
我还是再看一遍比较好
How is lke taking it?
艾克对此有何反应？
Like everybody else, sir. Hanging on by his fingernails.
和其他人一样,长官,在焦急等待
No, no! We must regroup according to Plan Six!
不,不!我们必须照方案六重新部署!
Hello? Hello? Can you hear me?
喂？喂？能听到吗？
I said we must regroup according to Plan Six.
我是说我们必须照方案六重新部署!
Nonsense!
废话!
If the panzers arrive, we still have time to use them.
如果装甲师能来还不算太晚
We'll drive to the coast!
我们乘车去海岸!
Shall we remove the files?
要销毁文件吗？
I don't care! I want to get to the front at once, to Normandy!
这我不在乎!我要马上去前线,去诺曼底!
Yes, general.
是,将军
-Where is everybody? -What?
－其他人在哪？ －什么？
I said, where is everybody?
我说其他人在哪？
I can't hear you.
我听不见
It's them bells.
是那口大钟
I've had them in my ears for 10 hours.
在我耳朵里响了足有十个钟头
Ding-dong, ding-dong.
叮－当,叮－当
Hey, sergeant, where's Major Lance?
嘿,中士,兰斯少校在哪？
We moved the CP to that building. The major's there.
指挥所转移到了那幢建筑,他在那
Get him, the colonel's here.
去找他,中校来了
What?
什么？
Hold it!
停下!
Colonel, am I glad to see you!
中校,见到你太好了!
Those bodies. Get those bodies down.
那些尸体,把那些尸体弄下来
Why are you leaving them up there?  Get them down!
怎么让他们留在上面？取下来!
But we've been under fire, sir.
我们一直处在火力之下
I know you have, but I don't care!
我知道,但我不管!
Get them down! Down!
快取下!取下!
-I don't want those boys left there. -Take a detail and cut them down.
－我不想让弟兄们留在那 －带一队人去办
-At once! -Yes, sir.
－马上去! －是,长官
Has there been a linkup between our forces and the troops from the sea?
我们的部队和海上的军队之间有接应吗？
I don't know, major. I don't even know if the landings took place.
不知道,少校,我连他们是否已经登陆都不知道
But I am sure we're gonna hold this town until the linkup does come.
我只知道必须守住这个镇直到接应部队前来
Whenever that is, today, tomorrow, till hell freezes over.
无论是今天,明天,还是要等到地狱冻结
For their sake, if for no other reason.
哪怕只看在他们份上
Show me the enemy positions.
告诉我敌人的位置在哪
Well, sir, the Germans' strong point is right there.
是,长官,德国人的据点就在那
That's over there on the hill. They've got no tanks yet.
就在那边的山上,还没有坦克
They've got heavy guns, mortars and machine gun positions at the top of that road.
他们在公路上方布置了重炮,迫击炮和机枪
How many men have you got?
你有多少人？
Not enough.
不够
Captain and Lieutenant Wilson will take A Company and reinforce Major Lance.
上尉和威尔逊中尉带Ａ连去增援兰斯少校
The rest of the command will follow us straight up that road.
其他的人跟我们一起向公路前进
Good luck, major.
祝你好运,少校
All right, A Company, fall out.
好的,Ａ连,离队
-Private. -Yes, sir.
－二等兵 －是,长官
It's a hell of a war.
真是地狱战场
It's a privilege to serve with you, colonel.
我愿意和您并肩作战, 中校
Well, God willing, we'll do what we came here to do.
但愿我们能完成我们来此的目的
Ready, sir.
准备好了,头
Move out!
出发!
The old man sure has changed since yesterday.
老头肯定是从昨天开始改变的
Or maybe it's just that we've changed...
也可能是我们改变了……
...since yesterday.
……从昨天开始
Lovat and his commandos have reached the bridge.
拉瓦特已率突击队抵达大桥
Bob, did you hear?
鲍勃,你在听吗？
Yes, I heard.
是的,我在听
"Sainte-Mere-Eglise captured by units of the 82nd Airborne."
“圣米尔伊格里斯已被八十二空降师占领”
" 101 Airborne driving on Utah."
“一○一空降师正在‘犹他海滩’推进”
That's good. Good.
很好,很好
Yes, but if we can't get off Omaha it doesn't mean a damn. We know it.
是的,是不错， 但如果不能从“奥马哈海滩”脱身就毫无意义,这我们都清楚
We'll have two cut-off beachheads, one in British zone and one at Utah.
我们拿下了两处滩头阵地,一处是英军区,一处是"犹他海滩"
...and the Germans in between.
……但是中间是德军
You guys engineers?
你们是工兵吗？
Yes, sir, 299th.
是,长官,第二九九特种工兵营
Where are your officers? Who's in charge here?
指挥官呢？这里由谁负责？
I guess I am, sir.  None of our officers made it in.
我想是由我负责,长官,指挥官都不在
What about your equipment? Those torpedoes work?
装备呢？爆破筒能用吗？
Yes, sir, we'll make them work!
是的,长官,当然能用!
-What's your name, sergeant? -It's Fuller, sir, John H.
－你叫什么,中士？ －Ｊ・Ｈ・弗勒,长官
You're Lieutenant Fuller from now on, whether you like it or not.
现在起你是弗勒少尉,不管你愿不愿意
You send some men down to the foot of that gully with those torpedoes.
派人带上爆破筒去溪谷底部
-You and the rest of the men follow me. -Yes, sir!
－你和其余的人跟我来 －是,长官!
All right, men! Let's move that equipment down here.
好了,弟兄们!带上装备离开这
-I got a rifle, sir. -Well, good for you, son!
－我有支枪,长官 －很好,小伙子!
The Rangers are ready, general.
“轻骑兵”在待命,长官
Okay, major, move them out.
好的,少校,叫他们出发
Captain, move them up.
上尉,让他们出发
Move them up!
出发!
-Well, Tom? -We're ready.
－什么事？ －我们准备好了
As ready as we'll ever be.
一切已准备就绪
It'll work. It's got to work.
会成功的,一定会成功
We're getting murdered here! We might as well move inland and get murdered!
我们在这会被干掉! 倒不如推进到内陆再死!
-You ready? -Yes, sir.
－准备好了？ －是,长官
You're gonna blow that roadblock for me.
给我把那个路障清除掉
When I give the word everything pops at once. Okay?
收到信号立刻行动,懂吗？
Yes, sir.
是,长官
First, we gotta blow a hole through that wire with bangalores.
我们先要用爆破筒在铁丝网上炸个洞
If that works, we'll pack everything we've got into that wall.
能成功的话就把所有炸药填到墙底下
All right, let's go!
好了,上!
All right, let's go! Go! Go!
行了,冲啊!冲!冲!
We must leave. The main highway is under aerial attack.
我们必须离开,公路干线遭到了空袭
You don't say!
不用你说!
Don't worry, Yank.
别担心,美国佬
He's dead.
他死了
Give me a cigarette. I'm dying for a cigarette.
给我一支烟,我想抽烟想得要命
You hurt bad?
伤得很重吗？
Shot down during the night.
夜里被击落了
He was gonna make sure of me, but I got him...
他想看我死了没有,被我干掉了……
...with this.
……用这个
You ever killed a man? I mean, face to face?
你杀过人没有？我是指,面对面地？
No.
没有
Neither had l, face to face.
我也没有,面对面地
I've been sitting here looking at him.
我一直坐在这看着他
Have you noticed anything peculiar about him?
你发现他有什么特别之处没有？
No.
没有
He's got his boots...
他的靴子……
...on the wrong feet.
……穿错了脚
He must have been in a big hurry, huh?
他一定非常匆忙对吧？
Is it bad?
严重吗？
Split wide open...
裂了个大口子……
...from the crotch to the knee.
……从胯部一直到膝盖
A medic came along and gave me a shot of morphine.
有个军医来过,给我注射了吗啡
I hope he'll be back before it wears off.
但愿他在药效失去前回来
He said he would.
他说他会的
Did he sew you up?
他替你缝合没有？
Well, when he came ashore he lost most of his equipment.
他上岸时把大部分器材都弄丢了
So he pinned it together...
所以他缝合时只能……
...with safety pins.
……用别针
Getting on toward night.
天就快黑了
You know something?
你知道吗？
I haven't fired my gun all day.
我整天都没开过一枪
I keep hearing shooting, but every time I get there, everybody's gone.
我不断听到枪声,但每次等我赶到,就没人了
Funny, isn't it?
真滑稽,是吧？
He's dead.
他死了
I'm crippled.
我瘸了
You're lost.
你迷路了
I suppose it's always like that.
我猜它一直都是这样
I mean war.
我是指战争
I wonder who won.
我想知道谁赢了
Okay, run me up the hill, son.
好了,送我上山,小伙子